Finding Aid for the Alec Hyatt King Papers, 1859-1998
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
- Monographic titles collected by King, 1859-1998, IX; Folder 379-450
  - Peters Edition. Edition Peters [history]. London: Peters, 1975, 8 pages; History of the music publishing firm, re-named Peters Edition in 1975. Inserted: Guest list for the Peters Edition reception at Kettner's restaurant on 16th Decmeber 1975. (Box 14, Folder 429)
  - Peters Edition. Ferneyhough. London: C. F. Peters, 1981, 26 pages (Box 14, Folder 430)
  - Pethes, Ivan. Flexible classification system of music and litterature on music: Preprint. Budapest: Centre of Library Science and Methodology 1967, 49 pages (Box 14, Folder 431)
  - Pulkert, Oldrich. Pokyny ke katalogizaci hudebnin Prague: Universitni Knihovna, 1966, 42 pages (Box 14, Folder 432)
  - Ricordi (Firm) Celebrazioni per il 150 anniversario della fondazione di Casa Ricordi. Milan: G. Ricordi, 1958, 40 pages; Issue 4, November 1958, or Tempo e musica. (Box 14, Folder 433)
  - Royal College of Organists (Great Britain) Catalogue of a collection of organiana. London: Royal College of Organists, 1968, 12 pages (Box 14, Folder 434)
  - Simeone, Nigel. Johannes Brahms 1833-1897: a catalogue issued to celebrate the 150th anniversary of his birth. London: Burnett & Simeone, 1983, 32 pages; Catalogue no. 8 (Box 14, Folder 435)
  - Sotheby Parke Bernet & Co. Catalogue of printed and manuscript music, autograph letters of musicians, and books on music and the theatre, playbills, photographs ...: day of sale, Tuesday, 15th May, 1979.. London: Sotheby Parke Bernet & Co., 1979, 64 pages (Box 14, Folder 436)
  - Staatsbibliothek Preussischer Kulturbesitz. Mendelssohn-Archiv. Fanny Hensel, geb. Mendelssohn Bartholdy, 14. Nov. 1805-14. Mai 1847: Dokumente ihres Lebens. Berlin: Staatsbibliothek Preussischer Kulturbesitz 1972, 12 pages (Box 14, Folder 437)
  - Staatsbibliothek Preussischer Kulturbesitz. Mendelssohn-Archiv. Ludwig van Beethoven: 1770 - 1970; Autographe aus der Musikabteilung der Staatsbibliothek Preußischer Kulturbesitz. Berlin: Staatsbibliothek Preuss. Kulturbesitz 1970, 36 pages; "Bearbeitet von Rudolf Elvers und Hans-Gunter Klein." (Box 14, Folder 438)
  - Stoph, Willi. Beethoven commemoration of the German Democratic Republic. Dresden: Verlag Zeit im Bild, 1970, 27 pages (Box 14, Folder 439)
  - Universidade de São Paulo. Escola de Comunicações e Artes. Biblioteca. Partituras existentes na Biblioteca da Eca dezembro de 1973. São Paulo: COM-ARTE, 1974, 50 pages (Box 14, Folder 440)
  - University of California, Berkeley. Autograph manuscripts of Ernest Bloch at the University of California. Berkeley: University of California, 1962, 20 pages (Box 14, Folder 441)
  - Unknown. Phyllis Tate 1911-1987. London: Unknown, 1987, 14 pages (Box 14, Folder 442)
  - Verband Deutscher Komponisten und Musikwissenschaftler. Aufgaben und Struktur der Musikerziehung in der Deutschen Demokratischen Republik. Berlin: Musikinformationsqentrum in Verbindung mit der Musikrat der DDR, 1966, 32 pages (Box 14, Folder 443)
  - Walton, Alexander. Architecture and music: a study in reciprocal values. Cambridge: W. Heffer & Sons, 1934, 33 pages (Box 14, Folder 444)
  - Watanabe, Ruth T. (Ruth Taiko) Preliminary checklist of works by Lully, Marpurg, Mattheson and Rameau, found in the Sibley Music Library Rochester, N.Y.: Sibley Music Library, 1972, 8 leaves (Box 14, Folder 445)
  - Westminster City Libraries. Central Music Library. Central Music Library. London: Central Music Library, 1952, 4 pages (Box 14, Folder 446)
  - Westrup, J. A. (Jack Allan), 1904-1975. Meaning of musical history (lecture given at Oxford on Nov. 21, 1945). London: G. Cumberlege, Oxford University Press 1946, 32 pages (Box 14, Folder 447)
  - William Barrow Collection. List of instruments. llandudno (Wales): The Collection, 1955, 4 pages (Box 14, Folder 448)
  - Wilson, Michael I., 1930- Bibliography of books on musical instruments in the Library of the Victoria and Albert Museum. London: Victoria and Albert Museum Library 1971, 45 pages (Box 14, Folder 449)
  - Wilson, Michael I., 1930- Musical instruments: a list of books and articles in the National Art Library. London: Victoria and Albert Museum, 1973, 56 pages (Box 14, Folder 450)
Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the Library's online catalog.
Subjects
Music; Music--Bibliography; Exhibition catalogs; Concert programs; Opera programs
Genres
Correspondence; Exhibition catalogs; Offprints
Associated Material
Separated Material
Forty-eight monographic titles were separated from the collection to be cataloged to the general collection, including a small number of scores and libretti.
Bayerischen Nationalmuseum Ausstellung Alte Musik instrumente noten und Dokumente aus drei Jahrhunderten: Katalog. Munich: Musikverlag Max Hieber, 1951.
Blom, Eric, 1888-1959 Schubert. London: Novello, undated.
Bodleian Library English music: guide to an exhibition held in 1955. Oxford: Bodleian Library, 1955.
Bodleian Library Felix Mendelssohn Bartholdy. Oxford: Bodleian Library, 1972.
Böhme, Erdmann Werner 150 Lüneburger Musiker-Namen (1532-1864) nach Akten aus dem Stadtarchiv Lüneburg. Lüneburg: no publisher, 1950.
British Phonograph Committee British Record: the gramophone record industry's services to the nation from 1898 to the present day. London: British Phonograph Committee, 1959.
Bruckner-Bigenwald, Martha, 1910- Anfänge der Leipziger Allgemeinen musikalischen Zeitung. Hilversum: Frits A.M. Knuf, 1965.
Chopin, Frederic, 1810-1849 Polonez = Polonaise: g-moll, 1817. Katowice: Bibioteka Glówna Panstwowej Wyzszej Szkoly Muzycznej w Katowicach, 1976.
Clucas, Humphrey, 1941- Lux hominum: a sequence for double choir. Ely: Oecumuse, 1992.
Clucas, Humphrey, 1941- My God, my God: anthem for SATB unaccompanied. Ely: Oecumuse, 1992.
Clucas, Humphrey, 1941- Stabat Mater: for chamber choir (with sooprano solo) and string quartet. Ely: Oecumuse, 1992.
Colchester, L. S. Cathedral Church of St. Andrew in Wells: a short history of the organs. Wells, Somerset: St. Andrew's Press, 1958.
Comité national pour la célébration du bi-centenaire de Jean-Philippe Rameau Célébration de Jean-Philippe Rameau, 1764-1964. Paris: édition Richard-Masse, 1965.
Deutsch, Otto Erich, 1883-1967 Schubert und Grillparzer: ein Vortrag. Vienna: Wiener Bibliophilen-Gesellschaft, 1949.
Deutsche Staatsbibliothek Neuerwerbungen ausländischer Musikliteratur, 1956-1957. Berlin: Deutsche Staatsbibliothek, 1959.
Emery, Walter, 1909-1974 Editions and musicians: a survey of the duties of practical musicians & editors towards the classics. London: Novello, 1957.
Exeter University Beethoven and England 1793-1855: catalogue of a bi-centenary exhibition at the University Library, March 2-25, 1970. Exeter: Exeter University, 1970.
Feldmann, Fritz, 1905- Historische Tänze der musikalischen und choreographische Weltliteratur. Hamburg: Tanzarchiv-Verlag, 1960.
Ferrers, Herbert Penelope. Libretto. 1927.
Fitelberg, Grzegorz, 1879-1953 Dwie pies´ni = Two songs. Katowice: Bibioteka Glówna Panstwowej Wyzszej Szkoly Muzycznej w Katowicach, 1979.
Harrison, Frank Ll. (Frank Llewellyn), 1905-1987 Time, place and music: an introduction to ethnomusicology. Amsterdam: Frits Knuf, 1971.
Haward, Lawrence, born 1878 Music in painting. London: Faber and Faber, 1956.
Herbert, A. P. (Alan Patrick), Sir, 1890-1971 Red pen. Libretto. >1927.
Hird, Richard Durham Cathedral organs. Durham: Dean and Chapter of Durham, 1991.
Hodgkinson, Terence Handel at Vauxhall. London: Victoria and Albert Museum, 1969.
Köhler, Karl-Heinz, 1928- Weimarer Tage für Musikbibliothekare 8. bis 12. Oktober 1973: Berichte, Referate. Berlin: Ländergruppe DDR in der Internationalen Vereinigung der Musikbibliotheken und dem Bibliotheksverband der DDR, 1974.
Leipzig (Germany). Musikbibliothek Quellenkwerke zur Handelforschung Katalog. Leipzig: Leipzig (Germany). Musikbibliothek, 1959.
Lindahl, Charles Preliminary census of unique books and collections of music in the Sibley Music Library. Rochester, N.Y.: Sibley Music Library, 1972.
Lindlar, Heinrich 100 Jahre Rob. Forberg Musikverlag. Wilhelmshaven: Heinrichshofen's Druck, 1962.
Mendelssohn-Bartholdy, Felix, 1809-1847 Paphlëis: ein Spott-Heldengedicht. Basel: Internationale Felix-Mendelssohn-Gesellschaft, 1961.
Musioł, Karol Mala Kantata Wolnomularska W.A. Mozart K.V. 623. Katowice: Slask, 1959.
Pierne, Gabriel, 1863-1937 Viennoise: suite de valses et corteges-blues. Paris: M. Senart, 1934.
Rowley, Gordon S. Annotated catalog of rare musical items in the libraries of the University of Iowa, Additions 1963-1972. Iowa City: University of Iowa, 1973.
Santiago, Francisco Development of music in the Philippine islands. Quezon City: University of the Philippines, 1957.
Schneider, Max F. (Max Ferdinand), 1905- Mendelssohn oder Bartholdy?. Basel: Internationale Felix-Mendelssohn-Gesellschaft, 1962.
Schoenberg, Arnold, 1874-1951 Moses und Aron. Libretto. 1957.
Schubert, Franz, 1797-1828 Sieben leichte Variationen = Siedem latwych wariacji: G-dur, 1810. Katowice: Bibioteka Glówna Panstwowej Wyzszej Szkoly Muzycznej w Katowicach, 1975.
Schubert, Franz Ludwig, 1804-1868 Praktische Musikdirektor; oder, Wegweiser für Musik-Dirigenten. Leipzig: C. Merseburger, 1864.
Shaw, Watkins, 1911-1996 First list of word-books for Handel's Messiah, 1742-83. Worcester: Printed for the author by Ebenezer Baylis & Son, The Trinity Press, 1949.
Shaw, Watkins, 1911-1996 Handel's conducting score of Messiah. Tenbury Wells: St. Michael's College, 1962.
Smith, William C. George Frideric Handel, 1685-1759; catalogue of an exhibition held during the Edinburgh Musical Festival, 23 August - 11 September, 1948. Edinburgh: National Library of Scotland, 1948.
Staatsbibliothek Preussischer Kulturbesitz. Mendelssohn-Archiv Felix Mendelssohn-Bartholdy. Dokumente s. Lebens. Ausstellg. zum 125. Todestag im Mendelssohn-Archiv d. Staatsbibliothek Preuss. Kulturbesitz, Berlin-Dahlem. 1.-30. Nov. 1972. Berlin: Staatsbibliothek Preuss. Kulturbesitz, 1972.
Staatsbibliothek Preussischer Kulturbesitz. Mendelssohn-Archiv Neuerworbene Autographe: Ausstellung im Mendelssohn-Archiv der Staatsbibliothek vom 15. September bis 15. Oktober 1974, Berlin-Dahlem. Berlin: Staatsbibliothek Preuss. Kulturbesitz, 1974.
Tovey, Donald Main stream of music. London: British Academy, 1938.
Trebble, T.? BBC Sound Archives: Examples of catalogue entries. London: BBC Sound Archives, 1971?.
Waggerl, Karl Heinrich, 1897-1973 Joseph Mohr, der Schöpfer des Liedes "Stille Nacht". Salzburg: Salzburger Kulturvereinigung, 1948.
Wallace, William Vincent, 1812-1865 Maritana. Libretto. 1928.
Wallmann, James L. Taphouse collection of musical tracts at the Library of Congress. unknown: unknown, 1988.